KEVIN LONG

Austin, TX | 512-975-0082 | devkev.long@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/devkevlong/</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/KLong75</u> | Portfolio: <u>kevinlong.dev</u>

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer. Based in Austin, TX. Background in the performing arts and education. Brings the passion and creativity of an artist, combined with the patient persistence, and skilled communication of a teacher, to work as a software engineer. Thrives on creative problem-solving and collaboration. Experienced at meeting deadlines under pressure. Loves the challenge of attempting to answer the question, "What if?".

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS, Responsive Web Design, Agile Methodology, Object-Oriented Programming, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, React, React Hooks, React Router, React Context, Material UI, Node, SQL, Sequelize, MySQL, Bootstrap, GitHub, Git Version Control, Google Fonts, Heroku, bcrypt, JSON Web Tokens, Handlebars, jQuery, Model-View-Controller, PWA, Service Workers, Email.js

PROJECTS

Vain Mainstream - The official web application for indie rock musician Vain Mainstream. SPA. Installable PWA with offline functionality. Users can listen to audio, download MP3s, watch embedded videos, and share on social media.

GitHub: github.com/KLong75/vain-mainstream | Deployed: vainmainstream.com

- **Role:** development, design, sole author
- Tools: React, Material UI, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Google Analytics, Google Fonts

MUSICOLOGY - Full Stack (MERN) social networking application for musicians.

GitHub: github.com/KLong75/musicology | Deployed: musicology-umekev.herokuapp.com/

- Role: Primary author and project manager
- **Tools:** MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, bcrypt, JSON web tokens, Google Fonts

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Freelance - Remote

Oct 2022 - Present

Design, Develop, Update, and Maintain fully responsive web applications that meet client specifications, exceed client expectations, function well, are intuitive to use, and look great on any screen size.

Key Accomplishments:

- Vain Mainstream Indie Rock Musician vainmainstream.com
 - Designed and developed SPA/PWA from client specifications
 - o Optimized audio and image compression resulting in 20% faster website
 - Update weekly with new audio and video tracks as they are released by client
 - Support client social media campaign with Google Analytics data
- Sam Hahn Travel Travel Agency klong75.github.io/sam-hahn-travel
 - Designed and developed SPA/PWA from client specifications.
 - Adjust design based on client feedback

Bootcamp Teaching Assistant, 2U - Remote

October 2022 - Present

Assist with instruction of the Full Stack Web Development Curriculum. Support students with class activities, homework assignments, projects, and technical issues.

Key Accomplishment:

• Plan and facilitate bi-weekly homework help sessions based on student need resulting in a 15% increase in student homework submissions.

1st & 2nd Grade Teacher, Austin Discovery School - Austin, TX June 2020 - June 2021Utilized clear communication and critical thinking skills to develop and implement lesson plans for all subjects across two grade levels.

Key Accomplishments:

- Used no-code platform Seesaw in conjunction with several other learning applications to successfully develop and implement an innovative online learning system for virtual learning, allowing students to learn effectively from home with minimal hands-on support from parents and guardians resulting in a 25% increase in assignment completion.
- Through virtual learning, assisted two struggling students in improving their reading assessment scores to on-target levels.
- Earned State Teaching Certification from Texas Education Agency

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Texas

Austin, TX

Bachelor of Arts in Theater Truman State University

Kirksville, MO